常见问题(FAQ)

[#notwork 某些东东不工作 (URL重写, 代理, 路径, ...)]
[#other 有没有其它类似的Web服务器]
[#chroot 对于chroot的支持是否在计划之中?]
[#usecase 在什么情况下使用Nginx比使用squid要好?]
[#imapexample 有没有人能给出一个完整的.conf配置文件来详细的解读一下怎么配置和测试 IMAP 模块， 而不只是关于 IMAP 的只言片语啊?]
[#smtpexample 怎么让Nginx成为以postfix做为后端的SMTP代理?]
[#loadbalancing Nginx使用什么算法来实现负载均衡? 它能实现基于连接数的负载均衡吗?]
[#proxy_buffering 我能关闭从代理服务器到后端服务器的缓存吗或者使用上传进度特性?]

某些东东不工作 (URL重写, 代理, 路径, ...)

例如： 如URL重写(rewrite)不工作了或者是unix的路径(/$PATH)的问题云云...

请仔细阅读 [NginxDebugging] 并且 逐行 查看错误日志。
如果你没找到错误 打起精神 试着到IRC或邮件列表里说明一下你碰到的问题。

有没有其它类似的Web服务器

Cherokee
Lighttpd (Lighty)
thttpd

关于各自的优缺点请使用自己喜欢的搜索引挚查找  ;-)

对于chroot的支持是否在计划之中?

有人知道吗？

在什么情况下使用Nginx比使用squid要好? 反之亦然。

大体上来说nginx主要用于反向加速代理而不是像squid那样做为常规代理服务器。Nginx的最大优势在于高负载情况下内存和CPU的低消耗。 我不认为squid能给你带来比nginx更好的性能。

怎么让Nginx成为以postfix做为后端的SMTP代理?

有人知道不？

Nginx使用什么算法来实现负载均衡? 它能实现基于连接数的负载均衡吗?

目前Nginx使用简单的轮巡算法，所以无法做基本链接计数的负载均衡。 这个可能会在将来的版本中有所改变。

> 我能关闭从代理服务器到后端服务器的缓存吗或者使用上传进度特性?

基于 太多人询问下面的问题:

我能为了得到上传进度而关闭代理的缓存吗
使用nginx我怎么才能给用户显示上传进度
...

到目前为止 (2007-Apr-26) 还没有办法关闭到后端服务器的缓存.

Nginx事件模块

accept_mutex

Syntax: accept_mutex [ on | off ]

Default: on

nginx 使用连接互斥锁进行顺序的accept()系统调用.

accept_mutex_delay

Syntax: accept_mutex_delay Nms;

Default: 500ms

如果一个进程没有互斥锁，它将延迟至少多长时间。默认情况下，延迟是500ms 。

debug_connection

Syntax: debug_connection [ip | CIDR]

Default: none

Since 0.3.54 this option support CIDR address format

This option gives you the ability to write debug log only for the clients of this IP/NET.

Several different directives are possible.

Example:

error_log /var/log/nginx/errors;
events {
  debug_connection   192.168.1.1;

}

devpoll_changes

devpoll_events

kqueue_events

epoll_events

Syntax: devpoll_changes

Default:

These directives specify how many events may be passed to/from kernel, using appropriate method.

The default devpoll values are 32, the rest are 512.

multi_accept

Syntax: multi_accept [ on | off ]

Default: off

multi_accept tries to accept() as many connections as possible after nginx gets notification about a new connection.

rtsig_signo

Syntax: rtsig_signo

Default:

nginx uses two signals when the rtsig method is used. The directive specified the first signal number. The second is plus 1.

By default rtsig_signo is SIGRTMIN+10 (40).

rtsig_overflow_events

rtsig_overflow_test

rtsig_overflow_threshold

Syntax: rtsig_overflow_*

Default:

These directives specifies how to handle rtsig queue overflows. When overflow occurred nginx flushes rtsig queue, then it handles events switching between poll() and rtsig. poll() handles consecutively all unhandled events, while rtsig periodicaly drains queue to prevent a new overflow. When overflow is handled completely, nginx switches to rtsig method again.

The rtsig_overflow_events specifies the number of events to be passed via poll(). The default is 16.

The rtsig_overflow_test specifies after which number of events handled by poll() nginx will drains rtsig queue. The default is 32.

The rtsig_overflow_threshold works in Linux 2.4.x only. Before to drain rtsig queue nginx looks in a kernel how the queue is filled up

The default is 1/10. "rtsig_overflow_threshold 3" means 1/3.

use

Syntax: use [ kqueue | rtsig | epoll | /dev/poll | select | poll | eventport ]

Default:

如果在./configure的时候指定了不止一种事件模型，那么可以设置其中一个，以便告诉nginx使用哪种事件模型。默认情况下nginx会在./configure时找出最适合系统的事件模型。

你可以在 这里 查看可用的事件模型以及如何在./configure时激活

worker_connections

Syntax: worker_connections number

Default:

通过worker_connections和worker_proceses可以计算出maxclients：

max_clients = worker_processes * worker_connections

作为反向代理，max_clients为：

max_clients = worker_processes * worker_connections/4

Since a browser opens 2 connections by default to a server and nginx uses the fds (file descriptors) from the same pool to connect to the upstream backend

References

http核心模块

指令

alias

syntax: alias file-path|directory-path;

default: no

context: location

This directive assigns a path to be used for the indicated location. Note that it may look similar to the root directive, but the document root doesn't change, just the file system path used for the request.

For example:

location  /i/ {
 alias   /spool/w3/images/;
}

The request "/i/top.gif" will return the file "/spool/w3/images/top.gif".

It is possible to use variables in the replacement path.

The alias directive cannot be used inside a regex-specified location. If you need to do this you must use a combination of rewrite and root.

client_body_in_file_only

syntax: client_body_in_file_only on|off

default: off

context: http, server, location

The directive enables to store a client request body in a file.

Please note that the file at the request completion will not be removed if the directive is enabled.

This directive can be used for debugging and for the $r->request_body_file method in the Embedded Perl module.

client_body_in_single_buffer

syntax: client_body_in_single_buffer

default: off

context: http, server, location

The directive(0.7.58+) specifies whether to keep the whole body in a single client request buffer. The directive is recommended when using the variable $request_body to reduce the operations of copying.

client_body_buffer_size

syntax: client_body_buffer_size the_size

default: 8k/16k

context: http, server, location

The directive specifies the client request body buffer size.

If the request body is more than the buffer, then the entire request body or some part is written in a temporary file.

The default size is equal to two pages size, depending on platform it is either 8K or 16K.

client_body_temp_path

syntax: client_body_temp_path dir-path [ level1 [ level2 [ level3 ]

default: client_body_temp

context: http, server, location

The directive assigns the directory for storing the temporary files in it with the body of the request.

In the dir-path a hierarchy of subdirectories up to three levels are possible.

For example

client_body_temp_path /spool/nginx/client_temp 1 2;

The directory structure will be like this:

/spool/nginx/client_temp/7/45/00000123457

client_body_timeout

syntax: client_body_timeout time

default: 60

context: http, server, location

Directive sets the read timeout for the request body from client.

The timeout is set only if a body is not get in one readstep. If after this time the client send nothing, nginx returns error "Request time out" (408).

client_header_buffer_size

syntax: client_header_buffer_size size

default: 1k

context: http, server

Directive sets the headerbuffer size for the request header from client.

For the overwhelming majority of requests it is completely sufficient a buffer size of 1K.

However if a big cookie is in the request-header or the request has come from a wap-client the header can not be placed in 1K, therefore, the request-header or a line of request-header is not located completely in this buffer nginx allocate a bigger buffer, the size of the bigger buffer can be set with the instruction large_client_header_buffers.

client_header_timeout

syntax: client_header_timeout time

default: 60

context: http, server

Directive assigns timeout with reading of the title of the request of client.

The timeout is set only if a header is not get in one readstep. If after this time the client send nothing, nginx returns error "Request time out" (408).

client_max_body_size

syntax: client_max_body_size size

default: client_max_body_size 1m

context: http, server, location

Directive assigns the maximum accepted body size of client request, indicated by the line Content-Length in the header of request.

If size is greater the given one, then the client gets the error "Request Entity Too Large" (413).

It is necessary to keep in mind that the browsers do not know how to correctly show this error.

default_type

syntax: default_type MIME-type

default: default_type text/plain

context: http, server, location

Assigns the default MIME-type to be used for files where the standard MIME map doesn't specify anything.

See also types

Example:

location = /proxy.pac {
 default_type application/x-ns-proxy-autoconfig;
}
location = /wpad.dat {

  rewrite . /proxy.pac;
 default_type application/x-ns-proxy-autoconfig;
}

directio

syntax: directio [size|off]

default: directio off

context: http, server, location

The directive enables use of flags O_DIRECT (FreeBSD, Linux), F_NOCACHE (Mac OS X) or directio() function (Solaris) for reading files with size greater than specified. This directive disables use of sendfile for this request. This directive may be useful for big files:

    directio  4m;

error_page

syntax: error_page code [ code... ] [ = | =answer-code ] uri | @named_location

default: no

context: http, server, location, if in location

The directive specifies the URI, which will be showed for the errors indicated.

Example:

error_page   404          /404.html;

error_page   502 503 504  /50x.html;
error_page   403          http://example.com/forbidden.html;
error_page   404          = @fetch;

Furthermore, it is possible to change the code of answer to another, for example:

error_page 404 =200 /.empty.gif;

If an erroneous answer is processed by the proxied or FastCGI server and this server can return the different answer codes, for example, 200, 302, 401 or 404, then it is possible to hide the code returned:

error_page   404  =  /404.php;

If you wish to return the error code as-is, OMIT the = from the error_page directive:

error_page   404  /404.php;

if_modified_since

syntax: if_modified_since [off|exact|before]

default: if_modified_since exact

context: http, server, location

The directive (0.7.24) defines how to compare time of file modification and time in request header "If-Modified-Since":

off — don't check "If-Modified-Since" request header (0.7.34);
exact — exact match;
before — file modification time should be less than time in "If-Modified-Since" request header.

index

syntax: index file [file...]

default: index index.html

context: http, server, location

Directive determines the file(s) which will be used as the index. It's possible to use variables in the name of file. The presence of the files is checked in the order of their enumeration. A file with an absolute path can be put at the end. Example using a variable:

index  index.$geo.html  index.0.html  /index.html;

If you want to automatically generate an index from a directory listing, useautoindex on.

internal

syntax: internal

default: no

context: location

internal indicates that the matching location can be used only for so called "internal" requests.

For external requests it will return the error "Not found" (404).

Internal requests are the following:

requests redirected by the instruction error_page
subrequests created by the command include virtual of the "ngx_http_ssi_module" module
requests changed by the instruction rewrite of the "ngx_http_rewrite_module" module

An example to prevent clients fetching error pages directly:

error_page 404 /404.html;
location  /404.html {
  internal;

}

Nginx 0.7.x introduces a new syntax for internal locations: @location

Example:

location / {
    root /var/www/html;
    error_page 404 @40x;

}
 
location @40x {
  root /var/www/errors/40x.html;
}

keepalive_timeout

syntax: keepalive_timeout [ time ]

default: keepalive_timeout 75

context: http, server, location

The first parameter assigns the timeout for keep-alive connections with the client. The server will close connections after this time.

The optional second parameter assigns the time value in the header Keep-Alive: timeout=time of the response. This header can convince some browsers to close the connection, so that the server does not have to. Without this parameter, nginx does not send a Keep-Alive header (though this is not what makes a connection "keep-alive").

The parameters can differ from each other.

Notes on how browsers handle the Keep-Alive header:

MSIE and Opera ignore the "Keep-Alive: timeout=<N>" header.
MSIE keeps the connection alive for about 60-65 seconds, then sends a TCP RST.
Opera keeps the connection alive for a long time.
Mozilla keeps the connection alive for N plus about 1-10 seconds.
Konqueror keeps the connection alive for about N seconds.

keepalive_requests

syntax: keepalive_requests n

default: keepalive_requests 100

context: http, server, location

Number of requests which can be made over a keep-alive connection.

large_client_header_buffers

syntax: large_client_header_buffers number size

default: large_client_header_buffers 4 4k/8k

context: http, server

Directive assigns the maximum number and size of buffers for large headers to read from client request.

The request line can not be bigger than the size of one buffer, if the client send a bigger header nginx returns error "Request URI too large" (414).

The longest header line of request also must be not more than the size of one buffer, otherwise the client get the error "Bad request" (400).

Buffers are separated only as needed.

By default the size of one buffer is equal to the size of page, depending on platform this either 4K or 8K, if at the end of working request connection converts to state keep-alive, then these buffers are freed.

limit_except

syntax: limit_except methods {...}

default: no

context: location

Directive limits HTTP-methods, accessible inside location.

For the limitation can be used the directives of modules ngx_http_access_module and ngx_http_auth_basic_module:

limit_except  GET {
  allow  192.168.1.0/32;
  deny   all;

}

limit_rate

syntax: limit_rate speed

default: no

context: http, server, location, if in location

Directive assigns the speed of transmission of the answer to client. Speed is assigned in the bytes per second. Limitation works only for one connection, i.e., if client opens 2 connections, then total velocity will be 2 times higher then the limit set.

If it is necessary to limit speed for the part of the clients at the server level, based on some kind of condition - then this directive does not apply. Instead you should specify the limit by assigning the value to the $limit_rate variable, as shown below:

server {
  if ($slow) {
    set $limit_rate  4k;
  }

}

limit_rate_after

syntax: limit_rate_after time

default: limit_rate_after 1m

context: http, server, location, if in location

The directive limits speed only after the first part was sent.

limit_rate_after 1m;
limit_rate 100k;

listen

syntax: listen address:port [ default [ backlog=num | rcvbuf=size | sndbuf=size | accept_filter=filter | deferred | bind | ssl ] ]

default: listen 80

context: server

The listen directive specifies the address and port accepted by the enclosing server {...} block. It is possible to specify only an address, only a port, or a server name as the address.

listen 127.0.0.1:8000;

listen 127.0.0.1;
listen 8000;
listen *:8000;
listen localhost:8000;

IPv6 address(0.7.36) are set in square brackets:

listen [::]:8000; 
listen [fe80::1];

When Linux (in contrast to FreeBSD) binds IPv6 [::], it will also bind the corresponding IPv4 address. If other non IPv6 server definitions already used this, the bind will fail. By using explicit addresses instead of [::] this will not be a problem. It is also possible to specify that this listen directive is only to bind the IPv6 address with use of the "default ipv6only=on" option. Note that this only affect this listen directive, the same server {...} block may very well listen to IPv4 as well, specified by other listen directives.

listen [2a02:750:5::123]:80;
listen [::]:80 default ipv6only=on;

If only address is given, the default port is 80.

If the directive has the default parameter, then the enclosing server {...} block will be the default server for the address:port pair. This is useful for name-based virtual hosting where you wish to specify the default server block for hostnames that do not match any [#server_name server_name] directives. If there are no directives with the default parameter, then the default server will be the first server block in which the address:port pair appears.

The listen directive accepts several parameters, specific to the system calls listen(2) and bind(2). These parameters must follow the default parameter.

backlog=num -- is assigned parameter backlog in call listen(2). By default backlog equals -1.

rcvbuf=size -- assigned to the parameter SO_RCVBUF for the listening socket.

sndbuf=size -- assigned to the parameter SO_SNDBUF for the listening socket.

accept_filter=filter -- is assigned name accept-filter.

. It works only to FreeBSD, it is possible to use two filters -- dataready and httpready. On the signal -HUP accept-filter it is possible to change only in the quite last versions FreeBSD: 6.0, 5.4-STABLE and 4.11-STABLE.

deferred -- indicates to use that postponed accept(2) on Linux with

. the aid of option TCP_DEFER_ACCEPT.

bind -- indicates that it is necessary to make bind(2) separately

. for this pair of address:port. The fact is that if are described several directives listen with the identical port, but by different addresses and one of the directives listen listens to on all addresses for this port (*:port), then nginx will make bind(2) only to *:port. It is necessary to consider that in this case for determining the address, on which the connections arrive, is done the system call getsockname(). But if are used parameters backlog, rcvbuf, sndbuf, accept_filter or deferred, then it is always done separately for this pair of address:port bind(2).

ssl -- parameter (0.7.14) not related to listen(2) and bind(2) syscalls

. but instead specifies that connections accepted on this port should work in SSL mode. This allows to specify compact configurations for servers working with both HTTP and HTTPS. For example:

listen  80;
listen  443 default ssl;

Example of the use of the parameters:

listen  127.0.0.1 default accept_filter=dataready backlog=1024;

location

syntax: location [=|~|~*|^~] /uri/ { ... }

default: no

context: server

This directive allows different configurations depending on the URI. It can be configured using both literal strings and regular expressions. To use regular expressions, you must use the a prefix:

~* for case insensitive matching
~ for case sensitive matching

To determine which location directive matches a particular query, the literal strings are checked first. Literal strings match the beginning portion of the query and are case-sensitive - the most specific match will be used (see below on how nginx determines this). Afterwards, regular expressions are checked in the order defined in the configuration file. The first regular expression to match the query will stop the search. If no regular expression matches are found, the result from the literal string search is used.

There are two ways to modify this behavior. The first is to use the prefix "=", which matches an exact query only. If the query matches, then searching stops and the request is handled immediately. For example, if the request "/" occurs frequently, then using "location = /" will expedite the processing of this request.

The second is to use the prefix ^~. This prefix is used with a literal string and tells nginx to not check regular expressions if the path provided is a match. For instance, "location ^~ /images/" would halt searching if the query begins with /images/ - all regular expression directives would not be checked.

To summarize, the order in which directives are checked is as follows:

Directives with the = prefix that match the query exactly. If found, searching stops.
All remaining directives with conventional strings. If this match used the ^~ prefix, searching stops.
Regular expressions, in the order they are defined in the configuration file.
If #3 yielded a match, that result is used. Otherwise, the match from #2 is used.

It is important to know that nginx does the comparison against decoded URIs. For example, if you wish to match "/images/%20/test", then you must use "/images/ /test" to determine the location.

Example:

location  = / {

  # matches the query / only.
  [ configuration A ] 
}
location  / {
  # matches any query, since all queries begin with /, but regular
  # expressions and any longer conventional blocks will be

  # matched first.
  [ configuration B ] 
}
location ^~ /images/ {
  # matches any query beginning with /images/ and halts searching,
  # so regular expressions will not be checked.

  [ configuration C ] 
}
location ~* \.(gif|jpg|jpeg)$ {
  # matches any request ending in gif, jpg, or jpeg. However, all
  # requests to the /images/ directory will be handled by

  # Configuration C.   
  [ configuration D ] 
}

Example requests:

/ -> configuration A
/documents/document.html -> configuration B
/images/1.gif -> configuration C
/documents/1.jpg -> configuration D

Note that you could define these 4 configurations in any order and the results would remain the same. While nested locations are allowed by the configuration file parser, their use is discouraged and may produce unexpected results.

How nginx Determines Which Path Matches

Most users will not need to know how nginx internally determines which path to use - know that it will choose the "most specific" match for your URI in a speedy and efficient manner. For those that are curious, however, read on.

All path strings are sorted alphabetically. nginx then proceeds to search down the list looking for matches until the request URI has a "higher" value then the current string in the sorted list. This is determined using the family of strcmp() functions - once strcmp() returns 1, then searching stops. Once searching stops, the last string which matched is used.

For example, lets say we have the following paths:

/
/a
/apple
/banana

Now, lets say the server gets the path "/az". nginx would begin search down this list. First, "/" would match, but "/ is less than "/az" so searching continues. "/a" also matches, but "/a" is still less than "/az" so we continue again. "/apple" does not match. The next string, "/banana", is greater than "/az" so searching stops and the last match, "/a", would be used.

Named Locations

Later versions of Nginx (>0.7.x) have Named Locations. These are location blocks that start with an @ symbol, and are treated similar to internal locations except that they preserve the original URI on internal redirects for error_page or try_files directives.

location / {

 try_files @joomla index.html;
}
location @joomla {
  rewrite ^(.*)$ /index.php?q=$1 last;

}

log_not_found

syntax: log_not_found [on|off]

default: log_not_found on

context: http, server, location

The directive enables or disables messages in error_log about files not found on disk.

log_subrequest

syntax: log_subrequest [on|off]

default: log_subrequest off

context: http, server, location

The directive enables or disables messages in access_log about sub-requests such as rewrite rules and/or SSI requests.

msie_padding

syntax: msie_padding [on|off]

default: msie_padding on

context: http, server, location

This directive enables or disables the the msie_padding feature for MSIE browsers. When this is enabled, nginx will pad the size of the response body to a minimum of 512 bytes, for responses with a status code above or equal to 400.

The padding prevents the activation of "friendly" HTTP error pages in MSIE, so as to not hide the more-informative error pages from the server.

Note that Chromium/Chrome have "friendly" HTTP error pages as well, but this feature will not send them the padding.

msie_refresh

syntax: msie_refresh [on|off]

default: msie_refresh off

context: http, server, location

This directive allows or forbids issuing a refresh instead of doing a redirect for MSIE.

open_file_cache

syntax: open_file_cache max = N [inactive = time] | off

default: open_file_cache off

context: http, server, location

The directive sets the cache activity on. These information can be stored:

Open file descriptors, information with their size and modification time;
Information about the existence of directories;
Error information when searches for a file - no file, do not have rights to read, etc. See also open_file_cache_errors

Options directive:

max - specifies the maximum number of entries in the cache. When the cache overflows, the longest-used items(LRU) will be removed;
inactive - specifies the time when the cached item is removed, if it has not been downloaded during that time, the default is 60 seconds;
off - prohibits the cache activity.

Example:

 open_file_cache max=1000 inactive=20s; 
 open_file_cache_valid    30s; 
 open_file_cache_min_uses 2;
 open_file_cache_errors   on;

open_file_cache_errors

syntax: open_file_cache_errors on | off

default: open_file_cache_errors off

context: http, server, location

The directive specifies to cache errors or not when searching a file.

open_file_cache_min_uses

syntax: open_file_cache_min_uses number

default: open_file_cache_min_uses 1

context: http, server, location

The directive defines the minimum use number of a file within the time specified in the directive parameter inactive in open_file_cache. ?If use more than the number, the file descriptor will remain open in the cache.

open_file_cache_valid

syntax: open_file_cache_valid time

default: open_file_cache_valid 60

context: http, server, location

The directive specifies the time when need to check the validity of the information about the item in open_file_cache.

optimize_server_names

syntax: optimize_server_names [ on|off ]

default: optimize_server_names on

context: http, server

Directive activates or deactivates optimization of host name checks for name-based virtual servers.

In particular, the check influences the name of the host used in redirects. If optimization is on, and all name-based servers listening on one address:port pair have identical configuration, then names are not checked during request execution and redirects use first server name.

If redirect must use host name passed by the client, then the optimization must be turned off.

Note: this directive is deprecated in nginx 0.7.x, use server_name_in_redirect instead.

port_in_redirect

syntax: port_in_redirect [ on|off ]

default: port_in_redirect on

context: http, server, location

Directive allows or prevents port indication in redirects handled by nginx.

If port_in_redirect is on, then Nginx will not add the port in the url when the request is redirected.

recursive_error_pages

syntax: recursive_error_pages [on|off]

default: recursive_error_pages off

context: http, server, location

recursive_error_pages enables or disables following a chain of error_page directives.

resolver

syntax: resolver address

default: no

context: http, server, location

TODO: Description

resolver_timeout

syntax: resolver_timeout time

default: 30

context: http, server, location

Resolver timeout in seconds.

root

syntax: root path

default: root html

context: http, server, location, if in location

root specifies the document root for the requests. For example, with this configuration

location  /i/ {
 root  /spool/w3;
}

A request for "/i/top.gif" will return the file "/spool/w3/i/top.gif". You can use variables in the argument.

note: Keep in mind that the root will still append the directory to the request so that a request for "/i/top.gif" will not look in "/spool/w3/top.gif" like might happen in an Apache-like alias configuration where the location match itself is dropped. Use the alias directive to achieve the Apache-like functionality.

satisfy_any

syntax: satisfy_any [ on|off ]

default: satisfy_any off

context: location

Directive solves access with at least one successful checking, executed by modules NginxHttpAccessModule orNginxHttpAuthBasicModule:

location  / {
 satisfy_any  on;
  allow  192.168.1.0/32;
  deny   all;
  auth_basic            "closed site";
  auth_basic_user_file  conf/htpasswd;

}

send_timeout

syntax: send_timeout the time

default: send_timeout 60

context: http, server, location

Directive assigns response timeout to client. Timeout is established not on entire transfer of answer, but only between two operations of reading, if after this time client will take nothing, then nginx is shutting down the connection.

sendfile

syntax: sendfile [ on|off ]

default: sendfile off

context: http, server, location

Directive activate or deactivate the usage of sendfile().

server

syntax: server {...}

default: no

context: http

Directive assigns configuration for the virtual server.

There is no separation of IP and name-based (the Host header of the request) servers.

Instead, the directive listen is used to describe all addresses and ports on which incoming connections can occur, and in directive server_name indicate all names of the server.

server_name

syntax: server_name name [... ]

default: server_name hostname

context: server

This directive performs two actions:

Compares the Host header of the incoming HTTP request against the server { ... } blocks in the Nginx configuration files and selects the first one that matches. This is how virtual servers are defined. Server names are processed in the following order:

full, static names
names with a wildcard at the start of the name — *.example.com
names with a wildcard at the end of the name — www.example.*
names with regular expressions

If there is no match, a [#server server { ... }] block in the configuration file will be used based on the following order:

the server block with a matching listen directive marked as default
the first server block with a matching listen directive (or implicit listen 80;)

Sets the server name that will be used in HTTP redirects if server_name_in_redirect is set.

Example:

server {

 server_name   example.com  www.example.com;
}

The first name becomes the basic name of server. By default the name of the machine (hostname) is used.

It is possible to use "*" for replacing the first or the last part of the name:

server {
 server_name   example.com  *.example.com  www.example.*;
}

Two of the above given names can be combined into one:

server {
 server_name  .example.com;
}

It is also possible to use regular expressions in server names, prepending the name with a tilde "~" like so:

server {
 server_name   www.example.com   ~^www\d+\.example\.com$;

}

The basic name of server is used in an HTTP redirects, if no Host header was in client request or that header does not match any assigned server_name. You can also use just "*" to force Nginx to use the Host header in the HTTP redirect (note that "*" cannot be used as the first name, but you can use a dummy name such as "_" instead):

server {
 server_name example.com *;

}
server {
 server_name  _ *;
}

Note that this has changed in 0.6.x and is now:

server {
 server_name _;

}

Since nginx 0.7.12, an empty server name is supported, to catch the requests without "Host" header:

server {
server_name "";
}

server_name_in_redirect

syntax: server_name_in_redirect on|off

default: server_name_in_redirect on

context: http, server, location

If server_name_in_redirect is on, then Nginx will use the first value of the server_name directive for redirects. If server_name_in_redirect is off, then nginx will use the requested Host header.

server_names_hash_max_size

syntax: server_names_hash_max_size number

default: server_names_hash_max_size 512

context: http

The maximum size of the server name hash tables. For more detail see the description of tuning the hash tables in Nginx Optimizations.

server_names_hash_bucket_size

syntax: server_names_hash_bucket_size number

default: server_names_hash_bucket_size 32/64/128

context: http

Directive assigns the size of basket in the hash-tables of the names of servers. This value by default depends on the size of the line of processor cache. For more detail see the description of tuning the hash tables in Nginx Optimizations.

server_tokens

syntax: server_tokens on|off

default: server_tokens on

context: http, server, location

Whether to send the Nginx version number in error pages and Server header.

tcp_nodelay

syntax: tcp_nodelay [on|off]

default: tcp_nodelay on

context: http, server, location

This directive allows or forbids the use of the socket option TCP_NODELAY. Only included in keep-alive connections.

You can read more about the TCP_NODELAY socket option here.

tcp_nopush

syntax: tcp_nopush [on|off]

default: tcp_nopush off

context: http, server, location

This directive permits or forbids the use of the socket options TCP_NOPUSH on FreeBSD or TCP_CORK on Linux. This option is only available when using sendfile.

Setting this option causes nginx to attempt to send it's HTTP response headers in one packet on Linux and FreeBSD 4.x

ReadMoreAboutTcpNopush

try_files

syntax: try_files file1 [file2 ... filen] fallback

default: none

context: location

This directive tells Nginx to test for each file's existence, and use the first found file as the URI. If none of the files are found, then the location fallback is called ("fallback" can be any name). fallback is a required parameter. It can be a named location or any guaranteed URI.

Example:

location / {

  try_files index.html index.htm @fallback;
}
 
location @fallback {
 root  /var/www/error;
 index index.html;

}

types

syntax: types {...}

context: http, server, location

Directive assigns the correspondence of expansion and MIME-types of answers. To one MIME- type can correspond several expansions. By default it is used these correspondences:

 types  {

  text/html    html;
  image/gif    gif;
  image/jpeg   jpg;
}

The sufficiently complete table of mappings is included and is located in the file conf/mime.types.

So that for that determined location's for all answers would reveal MIME- type application/octet-stream, it is possible to use the following:

location /download/ {
types          { }

 default_type  application/octet-stream;
}

变量

The core module supports built-in variables, whose names correspond with the names of variables in Apache.

First of all, there are the variables, which represent the lines of the title of the client request, for example, $http_user_agent, $http_cookie, and so forth.

Furthermore, there are other variables:

$arg_PARAMETER

This variable contains the value of the GET request variable PARAMETER if present in the query string

$args

This variable is equal to arguments in the line of request;

$binary_remote_addr

The address of the client in binary form;

$body_bytes_sent

(undocumented)

$content_length

This variable is equal to line Content-Length in the header of request;

$content_type

This variable is equal to line Content-Type in the header of request;

$cookie_COOKIE

The value of the cookie COOKIE;

$document_root

This variable is equal to the value of directive root for the current request;

$document_uri

The same as $uri.

$host

This variable is equal to line Host in the header of request or name of the server processing the request if the Host header is not available.

$http_HEADER

The value of the HTTP header HEADER when converted to lowercase and with 'dashes' converted to 'underscores', e.g. $http_user_agent, $http_referer...;

$is_args

Evaluates to "?" if $args is set, "" otherwise.

$limit_rate

This variable allows limiting the connection rate.

$query_string

The same as $args.

$remote_addr

The address of the client.

$remote_port

The port of the client;

$remote_user

This variable is equal to the name of user, authenticated by the Auth Basic Module;

$request_filename

This variable is equal to path to the file for the current request, formed from directives root or alias and URI request;

$request_body

This variable(0.7.58+) contains the body of the request. The significance of this variable appears in locations with directives proxy_pass or fastcgi_pass.

$request_body_file

Client request body temporary filename;

$request_completion

(undocumented)

$request_method

This variable is equal to the method of request, usually GET or POST.

$request_uri

This variable is equal to the complete initial URI together with the arguments;

$scheme

The HTTP scheme (i.e. http, https). Evaluated only on demand, for example:

rewrite  ^(.+)$  $scheme://example.com$1  redirect;

$server_addr

Equal to the server address. As a rule, for obtaining the value of this variable is done one system call. In order to avoid system call, it is necessary to indicate addresses in directives listen and to use parameter bind.

$server_name

The name of the server.

$server_port

This variable is equal to the port of the server, to which the request arrived;

$server_protocol

This variable is equal to the protocol of request, usually this HTTP/1.0 or HTTP/1.1.

$uri

This variable is equal to current URI in the request, it can differ from initial, for example by internal redirects, or with the use of index it is file with internal redirects.

References

Original Documentation

Browser模块

摘要

This module creates variables, the values of which depend on the request header "User-agent":

本模块的变量基于请求头(header)中的"User-agent":

$modern_browser - is equal to the value, assigned by directive modern_browser_value, if browser is identified as an modern browser;
$ancient_browser - 当等于指定给modern_browser_value的浏览器时，这个浏览器被认定为新版的浏览器;
$ancient_browser - is equal to the value, assigned by directive ancient_browser_value, if browser is identified as an old browser;
$ancient_browser - 当等于指定给ancient_browser_value的浏览器时，这个浏览器被认定为老版的浏览器;
$msie - is equal 1, if browser is identified as MSIE with any version;
$msie - 当浏览器为MSIE的任何版本时，这个值等于1;

If you don't need this module add --without-http_browser_module parameter to the ./configure call, at compile time.

如果不需要这个模块时，在编译的时候加上 --without-http_browser_module.

Example configuration 例如配置

Selection of the index file:

选择索引文件:

modern_browser_value "modern.";

modern_browser msie 5.5;
modern_browser gecko 1.0.0;
modern_browser opera 9.0;
modern_browser safari 413;

modern_browser konqueror 3.0;
index index.${modern_browser}html index.html;

Redirect for the old browsers:

定义老的浏览器:

modern_browser msie 5.0;

modern_browser gecko 0.9.1;
modern_browser opera 8.0;
modern_browser safari 413;
modern_browser konqueror 3.0;

modern_browser unlisted;
ancient_browser Links Lynx Netscape4;
 
if ($ancient_browser){
  rewrite  ^  /ancient.html;
}

指令

ancient_browser

syntax: ancient_browser line [ line... ]

default: no

context: http, server, location

Directive assigns the substrings, during presence of which in the line "User-agent", browser are considered as old.
Special line "netscape4" corresponds to regular expression "^Mozilla/[1-4] ".

ancient_browser_value

syntax: ancient_browser_value line

default: ancient_browser_value 1

context: http, server, location

Directive assigns value for the variables $ancient_browser.

定义 $ancient_browser的变量值.

modern_browser

syntax: modern_browser browser version|unlisted

default: no

context: http, server, location

Directive assigns which version of the browser is to be considered as modern.
As browser you can assign the values msie, gecko (Mozilla-based browsers) opera, safari, konqueror.

Of versions it is possible to assign in size X, X.X, X.X.X, or X.X.X.X. maximum values for each of their sizes respectively - 4000, 4000.99, 4000.99.99, and 4000.99.99.99.

Special value "unlisted" indicates to consider modern browser, not described by the modern_browser and ancient_browser directives.
Otherwise the neperechislennyy browser will be considered become obsolete.
If the headers do not contain "User-agent", the browser is considered neperechislennym.

modern_browser_value

syntax: modern_browser_value line

default: modern_browser_value 1

context: http, server, location

Directive assigns value for the variables $modern_browser.

定义$modern_browser的变量值.

References

Original Documentation new since 26.09.2006 version 0.4.3

Charset模块

This module adds the text encoding to the "Content-Type indicated" response-header.

Furthermore, module can reencode data of one encoding into another. It is necessary to note that the reencoding is accomplished only in one direction - from the server to the client, and only one-byte encodings can be reencoded.

Example configuration:

charset         windows-1251;
source_charset  koi8-r;

指令

charset

syntax: charset encoding|off

default: charset off

context: http, server, location, if in location

The directive charset adds the line "Content-Type" into response-header with indicated encoding. If this encoding is differed from that indicated in directive source_charset, then reencoding is carried out. The parameter "off" deactivate the insertation of the line "Content-Type" in the response-header.

charset_map

syntax: charset_map encoding1 encoding2 {...}

default: no

context: http, server, location

The directive charset_map describes the table of reencoding from one encoding into another. A table for the inverse reencoding is created using the same data. The codes of symbols are assigned in hexadecimal form. If no recorded symbols are in the range 80-FF they will be substituted with '?'.

Example usage:

charset_map  koi8-r  windows-1251 {
  C0  FE ; # small yu
  C1  E0 ; # small a

  C2  E1 ; # small b
  C3  F6 ; # small ts
  # ...
}

The complete table of conversion from koi8-r into Windows-1251 is distributed with nginx and is located in file conf/koi-win.

override_charset

syntax: override_charset on|off

default: override_charset off

context: http, server, location, if in location

This directive determines, to carry out reencoding for the response, obtained from the proxied server or from FastCGI-server, if in the response-header a "Content-Type" header already is. If reencoding is permitted, then as the initial encoding the encoding, indicated in the obtained answer, is used.

It is necessary to note that if the response was obtained in the subquery then, independent of directive override_charset, is always carried out reencoding from encoding of the response into encoding of basic demand.

source_charset

syntax: source_charset encoding

default: no

context: http, server, location, if in location

The directive source_charset assigns the initial encoding of response. If this encoding is differed from that indicated in directive charset, then reencoding is carried out.

References

Original Documentation

HttpReferer模块

摘要

This module makes it possible to block access to the site with the incorrect values of line "Referer" in the request header.

Keep in mind that it is easy to spoof this header; therefore, the purpose of using of this module consists not in 100% blocking of these requests, but in the blocking of the mass flow of requests, made from typical browsers. Also, consider that the typical browser does not always provide a "Referer" header, even for correct requests.

Example

location /photos/ {
  valid_referers none blocked www.mydomain.com mydomain.com;
 
  if ($invalid_referer) {
    return   403;
  }

}

指令

valid_referers

syntax: valid_referers [none|blocked|server_names] ...

default: none

context: server, location

This directive assigns a value of 0 or 1 to the variable $invalid_referer based on the contents of the referer header.

You can use this to help reduce deep-linking from outside sites. If Referer header is not accounted for in the list of valid_referers, then $invalid_referer will be set to 1 (see example above).

The parameters can be as follows:

none means the absence of "Referer" header.
blocked means masked Referer header by firewall, for example, "Referer: XXXXXXX".
server_names is a list of one or more servers. From version 0.5.33 onwards, * wildcards can be used in the server names.

References

Original Documentation

HttpLimit zone

本模块可以针对条件，进行会话的并发连接数控制。（例如：限制每个IP的并发连接数。）

__配置示例__

http {
: limit_zone   one  $binary_remote_addr  10m;

: ...

: server {

: ...

: location /download/ {
: limit_conn   one  1;
: }

指令

[#limit_zone limit_zone]
[#limit_conn limit_conn]

limit_zone

语法： limit_zone zone_name $variable the_size

默认值： no

作用域： http

本指令定义了一个数据区，里面记录会话状态信息。
$variable 定义判断会话的变量；the_size 定义记录区的总容量。

例子：

limit_zone   one  $binary_remote_addr  10m;

定义一个叫“one”的记录区，总容量为 10M，以变量 $binary_remote_addr 作为会话的判断基准（即一个地址一个会话）。

您可以注意到了，在这里使用的是 $binary_remote_addr 而不是 $remote_addr。

$remote_addr 的长度为 7 至 15 bytes，会话信息的长度为 32 或 64 bytes。 而 $binary_remote_addr 的长度为 4 bytes，会话信息的长度为 32 bytes。

当区的大小为 1M 的时候，大约可以记录 32000 个会话信息（一个会话占用 32 bytes）。

limit_conn

语法： limit_conn zone_name the_size

默认值： no

作用域： http, server, location

指定一个会话最大的并发连接数。 当超过指定的最发并发连接数时，服务器将返回 "Service unavailable" (503)。

例子：

limit_zone   one  $binary_remote_addr  10m;

: server {
: location /download/ {
: limit_conn   one  1;
: }

定义一个叫“one”的记录区，总容量为 10M，以变量 $binary_remote_addr 作为会话的判断基准（即一个地址一个会话）。 限制 /download/ 目录下，一个会话只能进行一个连接。 简单点，就是限制 /download/ 目录下，一个IP只能发起一个连接，多过一个，一律503。

References

原始文档

HttpLimitReqest模块

This module allows you to limit the number of requests for a given session, or as a special case, with one address.

Restriction done using leaky bucket.

Example Configuration

http {
    limit_req_zone  $binary_remote_addr  zone=one:10m   rate=1r/s;

 
    ...
 
    server {
 
        ...
 
        location /search/ {

            limit_req   zone=one  burst=5;
        }

指令

Syntax: limit_req_zone $session_variable zone=name_of_zone:size rate=rate

Default: none

Context: http

The directive describes the area, which stores the state of the sessions. The values of the sessions is determined by the given variable. Example of usage:

limit_req_zone  $binary_remote_addr  zone=one:10m   rate=1r/s;

In this case, the session state is allocated 10MB as a zone called "one", and the average speed of queries for this zone is limited to 1 request per second.

The sessions are tracked per-user in this case, but note that instead of the variable $remote_addr, we've used the variable $binary_remote_addr, reducing the size of the state to 64 bytes. A 1 MB zone can hold approximately 16000 states of this size.

The speed is set in requests per second or requests per minute. The rate must be an integer, so if you need to specify less than one request per second, say, one request every two seconds, you would specify it as "30r/m".

Syntax: limit_req zone=zone burst=burst [nodelay]

Default: none

Context: http, server, location

The directive specifies the zone (zone) and the maximum possible bursts of requests (burst). If the rate exceeds the demands outlined in the zone, the request is delayed, so that queries are processed at a given speed. Excess requests are delayed until their number does not exceed a specified number of bursts. In this case the request is completed the code "Service unavailable" (503). By default, the burst is zero.

For example, the directive

limit_req_zone  $binary_remote_addr  zone=one:10m   rate=1r/s;

 
    server {
        location /search/ {
            limit_req   zone=one  burst=5;
        }

allows a user no more than 1 request per second on average, with bursts of no more than 5 queries. If the excess requests within the limit burst delay are not necessary, you should use the nodelay:

            limit_req   zone=one  burst=5  nodelay;

HttpLog模块

ngx_http_log_module

实例

log_format  gzip  '$remote_addr - $remote_user [$time_local]  '
: '"$request" $status $bytes_sent '
: '"$http_referer" "$http_user_agent" "$gzip_ratio"';
access_log  /spool/logs/nginx-access.log  gzip  buffer=32k;

指令

access_log
log_format

access_log

语法： access_log path [format [buffer=size | off ] 默认值： access_log log/access.log combined

作用域： http, server, location

指令 access_log 指派路径、格式和缓存大小。参数 "off" 将清除当前级别的所有 access_log 指令。如果未指定格式，则使用预置的 "combined" 格式。缓存不能大于能写入磁盘的文件的最大大小。在 FreeBSD 3.0-6.0 ，缓存大小无此限制。

log_format

语法： log_format name format [format ...]

默认值： log_format combined "..."

作用域： http server

Directive log_format describes the format of a log entry. Besides general variables in the format it is possible to use variables which exist only at the moment of record into the log:

$body_bytes_sent, the number of bytes, transmitted to client minus the response headers, variable is compatible with parameter %B of module Apache's mod_log_config (this was called $apache_bytes_sent, before version 0.3.10)
$bytes_sent, the number of bytes, transmitted to client
$connection, the number of connection
$msec, the time with an accuracy to microseconds at the moment of the log entry
$pipe, "p" if request was pipelining
$request_length, the length of the body of the request
$request_time, the time of working on request in seconds
$status, status of answer
$time_local, local time into common log format.

The headers, transmitted to client, begin from the prefix "sent_http_", for example, $sent_http_content_range.

In the configuration there is always a predetermined format "combined":

log_format  combined  '$remote_addr - $remote_user [$time_local]  '
: '"$request" $status $apache_bytes_sent '
: '"$http_referer" "$http_user_agent"';

参考

原始文档

map

This module allows you to classify, or map a set of values into a different set of values and store the result in a variable.

Example:

map  $http_host  $name  {
  hostnames;
 

  default          0;
 
  example.com      1;
  *.example.com    1;
  test.com         2;
  *.test.com       2;
  .site.com        3;

}

One use for this would be to use a mapping in place of writing lots of server/location directives or redirects:

map $uri $new {
  default        http://www.domain.com/home/;
 
  /aa            http://aa.domain.com/;
  /bb            http://bb.domain.com/;
  /john          http://my.domain.com/users/john/;

}
 
server {
  server_name   www.domain.com;
  rewrite  ^    $new   redirect;
}

指令

map

syntax: map $var1 $var2 { ... }

default: none

context: http

map defines the mapping table which will be used to set a variable. There are three special parameters:

default — defines the value to be used where no match is found.
hostnames — it allows for an easier matching of values like host names, names with a starting dot may match exact host names and host names ending with the value, for example:

*.example.com  1; 

Instead of two entries

example.com    1;
*.example.com  1;

we can use only one

.example.com   1;

include — include values from a file. Multiple includes may be used.

map_hash_max_size

syntax: map_hash_max_size number

default: map_hash_max_size 2048

context: http

The directive sets the maximum size of a hash table to hold the variable map. For more details see the descriptions of hash settings Optimization section .

map_hash_bucket_size

syntax: map_hash_bucket_size n

default: map_hash_bucket_size 32/64/128

context: http

The directive sets the maximum size in a hash table to map variables. The default value depends on the size of the cache line processor. More see in the descriptions of hash settings in the Optimization section .

References

Original Documentation

Memcached

你可以利用本模块来进行简单的缓存以提高系统效率。本模块计划在未来进行扩展。

__配置示例__

server {
: location / {
: set  $memcached_key  $uri;
: memcached_pass   name:11211;
: default_type     text/html;
: error_page       404 = /fallback;
: }

: location = /fallback {
: proxy_pass       backend;
: }
}

指令

[#memcached_pass memcached_pass]
[#memcached_connect_timeout memcached_connect_timeout]
[#memcached_send_timeout memcached_send_timeout]
[#memcached_read_timeout memcached_read_timeout]
[#memcached_buffer_size memcached_buffer_size]
[#memcached_next_upstream memcached_next_upstream]

变量

$memcached_key

memcached_pass

语法： memcached_pass [ name:port ]

默认值： none

作用域： http, server, location

The backend should set the data in memcached. The memcached key is "/uri?args".

Since 0.5.9 the memcached key is now in $memcached_key.

memcached_connect_timeout

语法： memcached_connect_timeout [ time ]

默认值： 60000

作用域： http, server, location

The timeout for connecting to memcached, in milliseconds.

memcached_read_timeout

语法： memcached_read_timeout [ time ]

默认值： 60000

作用域： http, server, location

The timeout for reading from memcached, in milliseconds.

memcached_send_timeout

语法： memcached_send_timeout [ time ]

默认值： 60000

作用域： http, server, location

The timeout for sending to memcached, in milliseconds.

memcached_buffer_size

语法： memcached_buffer_size [ size ]

默认值： see getpagesize(2)

作用域： http, server, location

The recv/send buffer size, in bytes.

memcached_next_upstream

语法： memcached_next_upstream [ error | timeout | invalid_response | not_found | off ]

默认值： error timeout

作用域： http, server, location

Which failure conditions should cause the request to be forwarded to another upstream server? Applies only when the value in memcached_pass is an upstream with two or more servers.

HttpUserId

The module ngx_http_userid_module gives out cookies for identification of clients. For logging it is possible to use variables $uid_got and $uid_set. Remark: keep in mind variables $uid_got and $uid_set are not accessible in SSI, because SSI filter module working before userid filter.

This module is compatible with mod_uid for Apache.

Example

userid          on;
userid_name     uid;

userid_domain   example.com;
userid_path     /;
userid_expires  365d;
userid_p3p      'policyref="/w3c/p3p.xml", CP="CUR ADM OUR NOR STA NID"';

指令

userid

syntax: userid [on|v1|log||off]

default: userid off

context: http, server, location

Enables or disables issuing cookies and logging requested cookies:

on - enables version 2 cookies and logs them;
v1 - enables version 1 cookies and logs them;
log - do not send cookies, but write down incoming cookies to log;
off - do not send cookies, and don't write them to logs;

userid_domain

syntax: userid_domain [ name | none ]

default: userid_domain none

context: http, server, location

Assigns the domain for cookie. The parameter "none" doesn't issue domain for cookie.

userid_expires

syntax: userid_expires [ time | max ]

default: none

context: http, server, location

Sets the expiration time for the cookie.

The parameter set & send-out browser expiration time for cookie. Value "max" assigns the time on 31 December, 2037, 23:55:55 gmt. This is the maximum time that older browsers understand.

userid_name

syntax: userid_name name

default: userid_name uid

context: http, server, location

Assigns name to cookie.

userid_p3p

syntax: userid_p3p line

default: none

context: http, server, location

Directive assigns value for the header P3P, which will sent together with cookie.

userid_path

syntax: userid_path path

default: userid_path /

context: http, server, location

Sets the cookie path.

userid_service

syntax: userid_service number

default: userid_service address

context: http, server, location

Directive assigns the IP address of the server which gave out cookie. If not set, version 1 cookies set to zero, and for version 2 cookies the IP address of server.

References

Original Documentation

Addition模块

This module adds responses of other locations before and after the current location's response.

It is implemented as an output filter, the contents of the main request and subrequests to other locations are not buffered completely and are still sent to the client in a streaming fashion. Because the length of the final response body is unkown while sending the HTTP headers, the HTTP chunked encoding is always used here.

Installation

By default the module is not built, it is necessary to enable its build with

./configure --with-http_addition_module

at compilation time.

Example:

location / {
  add_before_body   /before_action;
  add_after_body    /after_action;

}

Limitations

Note that as of 0.8.17 no contents will be added if the current location is served as a subrequest itself. Consider the following example:

location /foo {
  add_before_body /bar;
}
 

location /bar {
 add_before_body  /baz;
}

Then accessing /foo won't get /baz inserted before the contents of the subrequest /bar.

Also note that at this time, only strings can be used in before/after body locations, not variables. So

location / {
  set $before_action /before_action;
  add_before_body $before_action;
}

will not work as expected (although the configuration file will still load properly).

Directives

add_before_body

syntax: add_before_body uri

default: no

context: http, server, location

Directive adds content of uri before the response body, issued as a result of the work of the assigned subrequest.

add_after_body

syntax: add_after_body uri

default: no

context: http, server, location

Directive adds content of uri after the response body, issued as a result of the work of the assigned subrequest.

addition_types

syntax: addition_types mime-type [mime-type ...]

default: text/html

context: http, server, location

Directive (since 0.7.9) allows you to add text only to locations of the specified MIME-types (defaults to "text/html").

(Before 0.8.17, this directive was mispelled as "addtion_types" in the source. This bug has been fixed in 0.8.17.)

References

Original Documentation

EmbeddedPerl

This module makes it possible to execute Perl directly within Nginx and call Perl via SSI.

Building Module at Compile-time

Unless built at compile-time, the module is not available. The default is to not build this module. If you want to enable this module, is necessary to specify --with-http_perl_module when running configure.

Your system must have Perl 5.6.1 or above.

Known Problems

This module is experimental; therefore anything is possible and bugs are likely.

If a Perl module performs protracted operation, (for example DNS lookups, database queries, etc), then the worker process that is running the Perl script is completely tied up for the duration of script. Therefore embedded Perl scripts should be extremely careful to limit themselves to short, predictable operations.
It's possible for Nginx to leak memory if you reload the configuration file (via 'kill -HUP <pid>').

Example:

http {

  perl_modules  perl/lib;
  perl_require  hello.pm;
 
  perl_set  $msie6  '
  sub {
    my $r = shift;
    my $ua = $r->header_in("User-Agent");
    return "" if $ua =~ /Opera/;
    return "1" if $ua =~ / MSIE [6-9] \.\d+/;
    return "";
  }
 ';

 
  server {
    location / {
      perl  hello::handler;
    }
  }

}

perl/lib/hello.pm:

package hello;
use nginx;
 
sub handler {
  my $r = shift;
  $r->send_http_header("text/html");
  return OK if $r->header_only;

 
  $r->print("hello!\n<br/>");
  $r->rflush;
 
  if (-f $r->filename or -d _) {

    $r->print($r->uri, " exists!\n");
  }
 
  return OK;

}
 
1;
__END__

指令

perl

syntax: perl module::function | 'sub {...}'

default: no

context: location

Directive establishes a function for the data location.

perl_modules

syntax: perl_modules path

default: no

context: http

Directive assigns additional path for Perl modules. Since version 0.6.7 this path is relative to directory of nginx configuration file nginx.conf, but not to nginx prefix directory.

perl_require

syntax: perl_require module

default: no

context: http

There can be multiple perl_require directives.

perl_set

syntax: perl_set module::function | 'sub {...}'

default: no

context: http

Directive establishes the function of variable ???

Calling Perl from SSI

Instruction format is as follows:

<!- # perl sub="module::function" arg="parameter1" arg="parameter2"... >

Methods of request object $r:

$r->args - method returns the arguments of request.
$r->filename - method returns the name of file, which corresponds to URI request.
$r->has_request_body(function) - method returns 0, if there is no request body. But if the request body exists, then the passed function is established and 1 returned. At the end of the body processing, nginx will call the established processor. Example usage:

package hello;
 
use nginx;
 
sub handler {

  my $r = shift;
 
  if ($r->request_method ne "POST") {

    return DECLINED;
  }
 
  if ($r->has_request_body(hello::post)) {
    return OK;
  }

 
  return 400;
}
 
sub post {
  my $r = shift;
  $r->send_http_header;
  $r->print("request_body: \"", $r->request_body, "\"<br/>");
  $r->print("request_body_file: \"", $r->request_body_file, "\"<br/>\n");
  return OK;

}
 
1;
 
__END__

$r->header_in(header) - retrieve an HTTP request header.
$r->header_only - true if we only need to return a response header.
$r->header_out(header, value) - set a response header.
$r->internal_redirect(uri) - method makes internal redirect to the indicated uri. Redirect occurs only after the completion of Perl script.
$r->print(args, ...) - sends data to client.
$r->request_body - method returns the request body of client when the body is not recorded into the temporary file.

So that the body of the demand of client is guaranteed to remain in memory, it is necessary to limit its size with the aid
of client_max_body_size and to assign sufficient size for the buffer using client_body_buffer_size.

$r->request_body_file — method returns the name of the file, in which is stored the body of the demand of client. The file must be removed on the completion of work. So that the body of the request would always be written to the file, it is necessary to indicate client_body_in_file_only on.
$r->request_method — method returns the HTTP method of the request.
$r->remote_addr - method returns IP address of client.
$r->rflush - method immediately transmits data to client.
$r->sendfile(file [, displacement [, length ] ) - transfers to client contents of the file indicated. The optional parameters indicate initial offset and length of transmitted data. Strictly the transmission of data occurs only after the completion of the perl script.
$r->send_http_header(type) - adds header to response. The optional parameter "type" establishes the value of line "Content-Type" in the title of answer.
$r->unescape(text) - decodes the text, assigned in the form %XX.
$r->uri - returns request URI.

References

Original Documentation

HttpGzipStatic

Before serving a file from disk to a gzip-enabled client, this module will look for a precompressed file in the same location that ends in ".gz". The purpose is to avoid compressing the same file each time it is requested.

在开始压缩创建硬盘上的文件之前，本模块将查找同目录下同名的.gz压缩文件，以避免同一文件再次压缩。

ngx_http_gzip_static_module was introduced in nginx 0.6.24. You must enable support at compile time:

nginx 0.6.24开始加入ngx_http_gzip_static_module . 编译时加上:

./configure --with-http_gzip_static_module

例如：

gzip_static on;
 
gzip_http_version   1.1;
gzip_proxied        expired no-cache no-store private auth;
gzip_disable        "MSIE [1-6]\.";

gzip_vary           on;

指令

gzip_static

syntax: gzip_static on|off

default: gzip_static off

context: http, server, location

Enables the module. You should ensure that the timestamps of the compressed and uncompressed files match.

启动模块。您应该确保压缩和解压文件的时间戳匹配。

gzip_http_version

See NginxHttpGzipModule

gzip_proxied

See NginxHttpGzipModule

gzip_disable

See NginxHttpGzipModule

gzip_vary

See NginxHttpGzipModule

HttpGeoIP

This module creates ngx_http_geoip_module variables based on the IP-address of the client matched against the MaxMind GeoIP binary files. This module appeared in nginx version 0.8.6.

本模块ngx_http_geoip_module的变量基于IP地址匹配MaxMind GeoIP 二进制文件. 这个模块开始出现在nginx0.8.6。

Precondition 首先

This module needs the geo databases and the library to read the database.

模块必需有geo数据库和读取数据库类

#下载免费的geo_city数据库
wget http://geolite.maxmind.com/download/geoip/database/GeoLiteCity.dat.gz
#下载免费的geo_coundty数据库
wget http://geolite.maxmind.com/download/geoip/database/GeoLiteCountry/GeoIP.dat.gz
#在debian中安装libgeoip:
sudo apt-get install libgeoip-dev
#其它系统，你可以下载并编译一个源文件
wget http://geolite.maxmind.com/download/geoip/api/c/GeoIP.tar.gz

在centos可以用yum安装:

yum install geoip

编译

./configure --with-http_geoip_module

例如

http {
    geoip_country  GeoIP.dat;
    geoip_city     GeoLiteCity.dat;
    ...

指令

geoip_country

syntax: geoip_country path/to/db.dat;

default: none

context: http

The directive indicates the path to the .dat file used for determining the visitor's country from the IP-address of the client. When set the module makes available the following variables:

dat文件用于判断访问者IP中的国家。当前模块 下可用的变量 :

$geoip_country_code; -国家名的前两个字母, 如, "RU", "US".
$geoip_country_code3; - 国家名的前三个字母, 如, "RUS", "USA".
$geoip_country_name; -国家名称, 如, "Russian Federation", "United States".

If you only need the country's name, you can just set the geoip_country database(1.1M), while the geoip_city database is much bigger(43M) and all the databses will be cached in memory.

如果你只需要国家，你只需设置geoip_country数据库(1.1M), 但城市的ip数据库就比较大(43M)并且将加载到内存当缓存。

geoip_city

syntax: geoip_city path/to/db.dat;

default: none

context: http

The directive indicates the path to the .dat file used for determining countries, regions and cities from IP-address of the client. When set the module makes available the following variables:

dat文件用于判断访问者IP中的国家、省，城市。当前模块 下可用的变量:

$geoip_city_country_code; -国家名的前两个字母, 如, "RU", "US".
$geoip_city_country_code3; - 国家名的前三个字母, 如, "RUS", "USA".
$geoip_city_country_name; -国家名称, 如, "Russian Federation", "United States".
$geoip_region; - 省，州或区名 (province, region, state, province, federal land, and the like), 如, "Moscow City", "DC".
$geoip_city; - 城市名称, 如, "Moscow", "Washington".
$geoip_postal_code; - 邮政编号.

References

Original Documentation

HttpXSLT

This module is a filter which converts an XML response with the aid of one or more XSLT templates.

This module was introduced in 0.7.8 and needs to be enabled via

./configure --with-http_xslt_module

Example:

location / {
  xml_entities       /site/dtd/entities.dtd;
  xslt_stylesheet    /site/xslt/one.xslt   param=value;
  xslt_stylesheet    /site/xslt/two.xslt;

}

指令

xslt_entities

syntax: xml_entities <path>

default: no

context: http, server, location

Specifies the DTD file which describes symbolic elements (xml entities). This file is compiled at the stage of configuration. For technical reasons it's not possible to specify entities in the XML being processed, therefore they are ignored, but this specially assigned file is used instead. In this file it is not necessary to describe structure of processed XML, it is sufficient only to declare necessary symbolic elements, for example:

  <! ENTITY of nbsp “  “>

xslt_stylesheet

syntax: xslt_stylesheet template [parameter[[ parameter... ]] default: no

context: http, server, location

Specifies the XSLT template with its parameters. Template is compiled at the stage of configuration. The parameters are assigned as shown:

  param=value

You can specify parameters either one per line, or separate multiple parameters with colon (“: ”) If the parameter itself contains the character “:”, escape it as “%3A”. Furthermore, libxslt requires that string parameters should be quoted by the single or dual quotation marks if they contain non-alphanumeric characters, for example:

  param1='http%3A//www.example.com': param2=value2

It's possible to use variables as parameters, for example, the entire line of the parameters can be substituted with one variable:

  location / {
    xslt_stylesheet /site/xslt/one.xslt
    $arg_xslt_params

    param1='$value1': param2=value2
    param3=value3;
  }

It is possible to specify several templates, in which case they would be chained together in the order of their declaration.

xslt_types

syntax: xslt_types mime-type [mime-type...]

default: xslt_types text/xml

context: http, server, location

Permit processing responses with specified MIME-types in addition to “text/xml”. If XSLT output mode is HTML, then the response MIME-type changes to “text/HTML”.

HttpSecureLink

This module computes and checks request URLs for a required security token. This module is not compiled by default and must be specified using the
这个模块计算和检测URL请求中必须的安全标识
这个模块没有默认编译，在编译Nginx时，必须使用明确的配置参数

--with-http_secure_link_module

argument to configure when compiling Nginx. Note that this module is only supported in nginx version 0.7.18 and higher.
来说明配置.这个模块在Nginx 0.7.18及以上版本中被支持.

Example usage:

location /prefix/ {
    secure_link_secret   secret_word;

 
    if ($secure_link = "") {
        return 403;
    }
}

指令

syntax: secure_link_secret secret_word

default: none

context: location

The directive specifies a secret word to verify requests. The full URL for a protected links follows this form:
这个指令明确一个安全关键字来审核请求。完整的被保护的URL如下表：

/prefix/hash/reference

hash is computed as as 使用md5('参考','安全密码')函数计算

md5 (reference, secret_word);

prefix is the scope of the location block, and must not be '/'. secure_link can only be used in non-root paths.
前缀是定位块的范围，绝对不能使用'/'。安全连接只能被用在非根目录路径。

变量

$secure_link

Automatically set to the reference component of the URL, isolated from the prefix and hash. If the hash is incorrect, an empty string is returned instead.
自动设置模块到URL的关联,分开前缀和HASH。如果HASH不正确，将返回空字符串。

HttpImageFilter

Version: 0.7.54+

This module is a filter for transforming JPEG, GIF and PNG images. It is not enabled by default to enable it, provide this option to ./configure when building nginx:
这个模块用来分发JPEG，GIF和PNG图片。这个没有默认开启，在编译nginx中通过./configure参数配置

--with-http_image_filter_module  

libgd is required to build and run the module. We recommend using the latest version of libgd.
编译和运行这个模块必须安装libgd库。我们推荐使用最新版本的Libgd.

Example Configuration

location /img/ {
    proxy_pass     http://backend;
    image_filter   resize  150 100;
    error_page     415   = /empty;

}
 
location = /empty {
    empty_gif;
}

指令

image_filter

Syntax: image_filter (test|size|resize width height|crop width height)

Default: none

Context: location

Specifies the type of transformation to apply to the image, one of the below:
详细的图片后缀类型如下：

test: checking that the response is indeed an image format JPEG, GIF or PNG. Otherwise, an error 415.
测试：测试确定图片文件的后缀格式为JPEG，GIF OR PNG。否则返回415错误

size: Gives information about the image in JSON format. For example,
尺寸：返回JSON格式的图片信息。例如：

{ "img" : { "width": 100, "height": 100, "type": "gif" } }

Or if an error occurs,
或者如果发生错误,

{}

resize: proportionally reduces the image to a specified size.
调整大小：缩略图片到特定的尺寸

crop: proportionally reduces the image to a specified size and trims extra edge.
切割：切割图片到特定的尺寸和特定的分辨率

image_filter_buffer

Syntax: image_filter_buffer size

Default: 1M

Context: http, server, location

Sets the maximum size for reading the image.
设置读取文件的最大的尺寸

image_filter_jpeg_quality

Syntax: image_filter_jpeg_quality [0...100]

Default: 75

Context: http, server, location

Sets the rate of loss of information when processing the images as JPEG. The maximum recommended value is 95.
设置处理JPEG图片的丢失信息率.推荐的最大值为95

image_filter_transparency

Syntax: image_filter_transparency on|off

Default: on

Context: http, server, location

This directive allows you to disable image transparency in GIF and palette-based PNG to improve image resampling quality.
这个指令容许你关闭GIF图片的透明度和 PNG图片质量

True color PNG alpha-channels are always preserved despite this setting.
真彩色PNG图片保存忽略设定

Note: Grayscale PNG's are untested, but should be handled as truecolor PNGs.
注释：灰度PNG图片未被设置，但应该被作为真彩色PNG图片处理

References

Original Documentation

MailCore

Nginx is able to handle and proxy the following mail protocols:
Nginx 能够处理和代理以下邮件协议:

IMAP
POP3
SMTP

认证

nginx uses external HTTP-like server to learn which IMAP/POP backend it should connect to.
nginx的IMAP／POP后端处理类似HTTP服务器的连接方式。

nginx passes authorization information in HTTP headers:
nginx 在HTTP头里传递授权信息:

GET /auth HTTP/1.0
Host: auth.server.hostname
Auth-Method: plain
Auth-User: user
Auth-Pass: password
Auth-Protocol: imap
Auth-Login-Attempt: 1
Client-IP: 192.168.1.1

The good response is:
正常的回应是:

HTTP/1.0 200 OK      # this line is actually ignored and may not exist at all 这行可能被忽略或者不可能都存在
Auth-Status: OK
Auth-Server: 192.168.1.10
Auth-Port: 110
Auth-User: newname   # you may override the user name to login to a backend  你可以重写用户名登录后端

When authenticating with APOP for POP3, you must return Auth-Pass as well:
当在POP3中使用APOP协议时，你必须返回验证密码如下:

HTTP/1.0 200 OK      # this line is actually ignored and may not exist at all
Auth-Status: OK
Auth-Server: 192.168.1.10
Auth-Port: 110
Auth-User: newname   # you may override the user name to login to a backend
Auth-Pass: password  # this must be the user's password in cleartext 这里必须是明文形式的用户密码

The failed response is:
失败的回应是:

HTTP/1.0 200 OK      # this line is actually ignored and may not exist at all
Auth-Status: Invalid login or password
Auth-Wait: 3         # nginx will wait 3 seconds before reading  Nginx在读之前等待3秒
# client's login/passwd again

指令

auth

Renamed to pop3_auth in 0.5.15

imap_capabilities

syntax: imap_capabilities "capability1" ["capability2" .. "capabilityN"]

default: "IMAP4" "IMAP4rev1" "UIDPLUS"

context: main, server

With this directive you can set the list of IMAP protocol extensions presented to the client upon issuing the IMAP command CAPABILITY. STARTTLS is automatically added if you enable the starttls directive.
使用这条指令你可以设置IMAP协议列表来扩展现有的客户端上的IMAP的命令CAPABILITY。如果你启用了STARTTLS那么STARTTLS命令将自动加入。

The current list of standardized IMAP expansions is published on www.iana.org.
现在所列出的标准的IMAP扩展发布在www.iana.org上。

mail {
  imap_capabilities NAMESPACE SORT QUOTA;
}

Will the defaults be also set, I haven't see this in the source?! (al 2007-05-11)
这个设置了默认了？我在源码中没有看到！

imap_client_buffer

syntax: imap_client_buffer size

default: 4K/8K

context: main, server

With this directive you can set the read buffer for IMAP commands. The default value is equal to the size of a page (this can be either 4K or 8K depending on the platform).

listen

syntax: listen address:port [ bind ]

default: no

context: server

The directive specifies the address and port, on which the server accepts requests. It is possible to specify address or port only, besides, an address can be the server name, for example:
当服务器接收请求时，这条指令指定地址和端口。这个可能只知道地址或者端口，另外，地址可能是服务器名，例如：

listen 127.0.0.1:8000;
listen 127.0.0.1;

listen 8000;
listen *:8000;
listen localhost:8000;

IPv6 address(>=0.7.58) are set in square brackets:

listen  [::]:8000; 
listen  [fe80::1];

In directive listen it is possible to indicate the system call bind(2).
listen指令可能显示显示系统命令 bind.

bind -- indicates that it is necessary to make bind(2) separately for this pair of address:port. If several directives listen with identical port but with different addresses and one of the directives listen to all addresses for this port (*:port) then Nginx will make bind(2) only to *:port. In this case the address is determined by the system call getsockname().
bind -- bind指令必须是绑定一对 地址：端口。如果多个指令监听不同地址的相同的端口，另一个指令监听所有地址的端口(*:端口号)，这样的话Nginx将指执行 bind的 *:端口号 .这样的话地址只能是系统命令getsockname()的值。

pop3_auth

syntax: pop3_auth [plain] [apop] [cram-md5]

default: plain

context: main, server

With this directive you can set the permitted methods of authentication for POP3 clients:
使用这条指令你可以设置验证POP3客户端的验证方法:

plain - USER/PASS , AUTH PLAIN , AUTH LOGIN
apop - APOP
cram-md5 - AUTH CRAM-MD5

pop3_capabilities

syntax: pop3_capabilities "capability1" ["capability2" .. "capabilityN"]

default: "TOP" "USER" "UIDL"

context: main, server

With this directive you can set the list of POP3 protocol extensions presented to the client upon issuing the POP3 command CAPA. STLS is automatically added if you enable the starttls directive and SASL is added by the directive auth.
使用这条指令你可以设置 POP3 协议 列表来扩展现有客户端上的POP3命令CAPA。 如果你启用了starttls指令STLS将会自动被添加，通过auth，SASL也将被添加。

protocol

syntax: protocol [ pop3 | imap | smtp ] ;

default: IMAP

context: server

This directive set the protocol for this server block.
这条指令设置了服务器块的协议

> server

syntax: server {...}

default: no

context: mail

Directive assigns configuration for the virtual server.
指令指定虚拟服务器的配置

There is no clear separation of the virtual servers ip-based and name-based (the value of the line "Host" header in the request).
这里不区分基于IP的虚拟服务器和基于命名的虚拟服务器（Host指从请求头中获得）

Instead of this by directives listen are described all addresses and ports, on which it is necessary to assume connections for this server, and in directive server_name are indicated all names of servers. Example configurations are described in tuning of virtual servers.
可以替代这个的listen指令描述了连接服务器的所有的地址和端口，和纸条指令的server_name显示了所有的服务器命名。例如 以下配置描述了虚拟服务器的调度

server_name

syntax: server_name name fqdn_server_host

default: The name of the host, obtained through gethostname()

context: mail, server

Directive assigns the names of virtual server, for example:

server {
  server_name   example.com  www.example.com;
}

The first name becomes the basic name of server. By default the name of the machine (hostname) is used. It is possible to use "*" for replacing the first part of the name:
第一个名称被默认为服务器的基本名词.被当作默认的机器名使用,这个也可能被*所代替。

server {

  server_name   example.com  *.example.com;
}

Two of the given name of the above example can be combined into one:
2个给定的名词在以上的例子中被合并成一个

server {
  server_name  .example.com;
}

The basic name of server is used in an HTTP redirects, if no a "Host" header was in client request or that header does not match any assigned server_name. You can also use just "*" to force Nginx to use the "Host" header in the HTTP redirect (note that "*" cannot be used as the first name, but you can use a dummy name such as "_" instead):
HTTP重定向中使用了服务器基本名称，如果客户端请求中没有"host"头或者头中没知道server_name.你可以使用“＊”来强制Nginx在HTTP重定向中使用"Host"头（注释： "*"不能作为第一命名可以使用"_"代替）

server {
  server_name example.com *;
}
server {
  server_name _ *;
}

smtp_auth

syntax: smtp_auth [login] [plain] [cram-md5] ;

default: login plain

context: main, server

With this directive you can set the permitted methods of authentication for SMTP clients:
使用这个命令你可以设置SMTP客户端的验证方法

login - AUTH LOGIN
plain - AUTH PLAIN
cram-md5 - AUTH CRAM-MD5

smtp_capabilities

syntax: smtp_capabilities “capability1” [“capability2” .. “capabilityN”]

default: no

context: main, server

With this directive you can set the list of SMTP protocol extensions presented to the client upon issuing the EHLO command. This list is automatically extended by the methods enabled with the directive smtp_auth.
使用这条指令你可以设置SMTP协议扩展现有的客户端通过使用EHLO命令.使用smtp_auth指令这个列表将被自动扩展。

The current list of standardized SMTP expansions is published on www.iana.org . 现在标准的SMTP扩展列表发布在www.iana.org

so_keepalive

syntax: so_keepalive on|off;

default: off

context: main, server

With this directive you can set the socket SO_KEEPALIVE option for the connection to the IMAP/POP3 backend. In FreeBSD the keepalive option is used for all connections and can be turned off through setsockopt no (see sysctl net.inet.tcp.always_keepalive).
通过使用这条指令你可以设置socket连接IMAP／POP3的SO——KEEPALIVE选项。在FREEBSD中这个 keepalive(保持存活) 选项在所有的连接中都有效并且可以使用setsockopt no来关闭。

timeout

syntax: timeout milliseconds;

default: 60000

context: main, server

With this directive you can set the time out for proxied connections to the back end.
使用这条指令你可以设置 代理连接的超时时间

MailProxy

Nginx can proxy IMAP, POP3, and SMTP protocols.
Ngin可以代理IMAP，POP3和SMTP协议

指令

proxy

syntax: proxy on | off

default: off

context: mail, server

With this directive you can enable or disable the proxy for mail.
使用这条指令你可以开启和关闭邮件代理

proxy_buffer

syntax: proxy_buffer size

default: 4K/8K

context: mail, server

With this directive you can set the buffer size for the proxy connection. The default value is equal to the size of a page (this can be either 4K or 8K depending on the platform).
使用这条指令你可以设置代理连接的缓存大小。默认值为页面的大小(这个根据平台的不同可能是4K或者8K）

proxy_pass_error_message

syntax: proxy_pass_error_message on | off

default: off

context: mail, server

With this directive you can pass authentification error messages obtained from the backend back to the client. Usually if authorization in nginx passed successfully then the backend cannot return errors back to the client.
通过这条指令你可以使得客户端忽略从后端获得的验证错误消息.通常验证成不会返回错误消息到客户端。

But for some POP3 servers errors in response to correct password is a regular behavior. For example CommuniGatePro notifies user about overcrowding of the mailbox (or other events) periodically issuing an error in authorization. In this case is worth indicating proxy_error_message on.
但是在POP3服务器中错误是用来更重密码。例如CommuniGatePro 通过验证返回邮箱收件箱已满的错误来通知用户，这样的代理错误信息是很有意义的。

proxy_timeout

syntax: proxy_timeout time

default: 24h

context: mail, server

With this directive you can set the timeout for the proxy connection.
使用这条指令你可以设置代理连接的超时时间。

xclient

syntax: xclient on | off

default: on

context: mail, server

With this directive you can enable or disable the command XCLIENT with the connection to SMTP backend. This allows the backend to enforce limitations on the client based on IP/HELO/LOGIN.
使用这条指令你可以开启或者关闭命令XCLIENT的SMTP后端连接.这个使得后端强制可以通过IP／HELO／LOGIN限定客户端

If xclient is enabled then nginx first transfers to the backend:
如果xclient被启用，nginx首先转换到后端

EHLO server_name

Then:

XCLIENT PROTO=ESMTP HELO=client_helo ADDR=client_ip LOGIN=authentificated_user NAME=[UNAVAILABLE] 